Well, congratulations, Kate. Obviously,
the the team thought, you know, you were
a fit. If a Lions fan were to ask you
kind of what what do you bring to the
table uh on Sundays? What would how' you
answer that question?
>> Yeah, I would say I'm a smart,
hardworking guy who's, you know, going
to do all I can to get the job done,
make the people around me better, um,
and, you know, just do all I can to help
this team win and achieve what we want
to.
>> Kate, I'm really curious about the the
journey to center. Um, you obviously did
it, I think maybe one game in college,
first two years as a pro guard. Um, you
know, what went in the decision to to
move you there and how much room maybe
do you think you still have to to grow
in that position?
>> Yeah, you know, it was just the position
that came open and um I got an
opportunity there and um just started
playing it, started learning it and um I
still feel like I'm on the rise at the
position. Um, you know, I've come a long
way, but I feel like I'm just now
getting to my getting on my way up. So,
feel like I've got a long way to go and,
um, I'm excited for the journey.
>> Did you have much interaction with the
Lions in the pre-draft process? I know
Senior Bowl Hank was working with you
guys. What, I guess, what conversations
maybe did you have way back then, if
any?
>> Yeah, Senior Bowl. Um, couple
conversations, you know, um, nothing
nothing out of the ordinary. Um, so
>> what about the just the fit here for
you? Why why the Lions? Why was this
your choice?
>> Yeah, I love the brand of football they
play. Um, I feel like I would have fit
in here coming into free agency. I uh,
you know, I felt like this was a team
where um, they they fit what I do and I
fit what they do. So, um, really looking
forward to it.
>> Kate, how would you describe that brand
of football that you're talking about?
>> Hard-nosed, grit, obviously, you know,
you see it all around the building. Um,
but I feel like I just I play into what
they do and and I was very very
interested when um going through the
free free agency thing. Um,
super excited, man.
>> Obviously, none of us have ever been in
that situation, right? But can you
explain? A lot of people on the outside
just think it's about money or
opportunity, but when you sit down
before free agency to kind of assess
what teams you might want to go to,
explain that that thought process like
identifying what fits you. you look at
what you want as a as a player, as a
person, and um obviously coach Dan like
my kind of guy and um I feel like I'm
like I'm his kind of guy. So you look at
stuff like that, you look at the brand
of football they play, like I said,
hard-nosed and um you know, want to move
people vertically and get the run game
going. Um so yeah, that that all that
stuff kind of goes into um goes into
play. Just going back to the versatility
aspect of things. How do you feel like
that cross trainining has kind of helped
you develop as the best overall football
player?
>> Um I think it's helped me a ton. You
know, in college I played all five
positions and just you know, never
feeling like I had to stick with one.
Just keep showing up and doing what
whatever was needed of me um from the
team and you know I I took pride in that
and just tried to better me wherever I
was on the field.
>> Feel like playing guard taught you
anything about tackle or playing tackle
taught you anything about center? Do you
feel like that helped you in any way?
>> Yeah, you definitely get um different
perspective from oppositions. You know,
um center is a little different. The
nuances are different from guard and
tackle a little bit different than
guard. So, you just kind of learn as you
go and um and make the most of it.
>> Hey, did you and Tate overlap at all
when you were arriving at Georgia? And
do you know him at all?
>> No, we didn't overlap, but we've got a
ton of mutual friends and um already
spoke to them and looking forward to
forging that relationship. Did you check
in at all with with Hen and Hooker
before coming here just maybe to get a
inside the building perspective of the
organization?
>> Um, me and Hennon were in Carolina
together, so I mean we've been we've
been tight obviously at Tennessee
together. Um, but nothing about Detroit,
you know, that's just that's my guy. So,
>> how about Frank Ragnau? I know it's a a
player removed at the center position,
but just maybe what he meant to you in
your career if you ever looked up to him
and kind of again I know there's a
player between you but fill in his shoes
and some
>> absolutely hell of a player like had a
incredible career here. Um loved what he
put on tape was really a guy I studied
um when I moved to center just the way
that he played and and try to model my
game after that. um you know just my
kind of guy and in the sense of how he
plays the game and how he goes about his
work.
>> You come from a football family. What
was it like to share the news of this
extension with them?
>> Man, incredible. Like family so excited.
I'm so excited. Um it's been a long
journey to get here and a lot of ups and
downs, but I'm incredibly blessed and
and grateful and thankful for the
opportunity.
>> You got a taste of playoff football last
year. for the first time in your career,
this team obviously has those kind of
ambitions. Just what kind of motivation
is it for you to get back there and
potentially go even further?
>> Yeah, absolutely. They're nothing better
than playoff football. I mean, it's a
it's a different animal and um the goal
is to win a Super Bowl. Um every year,
no matter where you are, that's the
goal. So, um when you get a taste of
that playoff football, it's it's
different.
>> Did it feel different to you? Just the
>> Absolutely. The energy, the energy of
the game is different. The fans energy
like I mean it's definitely a different
beast and you know I can't wait to
experience it here.
>> This line's going to look a whole lot
different than it has in past years,
right? Taylor Decker's gone. Glasgow,
you're part of sort of the new, you
know, generation of of linemen here. We
talked to Larry earlier. What do you
what do you what does that mean to you
to be a part of that and what do you
think the two of you can kind of help
this line do? Yeah, I'm just incred
incredibly excited to compete and um and
for the opportunity, you know, go out
there and and put my best foot forward
every day and try to be my best and and
make the people around me better.
>> A lot of people talk about the the
mental aspect of of being a center and
how much, you know, study that takes.
Where are you in in that part of your
journey of of becoming a a true center?
>> Yeah, I feel like I've learned a ton. I
feel like um you know, I command the
huddle. um get everybody on the same
page. Um you know, communicate with the
guys around me and and be on the same
page as a quarterback. That's the that's
the main goal. Make sure he's protected
and uh you know, keep hits off of him
and keep hits off the off the backs. So,
I feel like I'm I'm good in that sense.
Um feel like I'm a pretty smart player,
high IQ, and and you know, put a lot of
work into it.
>> You have a chance to connect with Jared
yet? And what kind of relationship can
you guys forge between now and the
beginning of camp? if any at all.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I've talked to him um a lot
of time between now and then. So I I I
think we'll I think we'll hit it off. He
seems like a great dude and uh I'm
excited for it.
>> Just going back to the studying aspect,
what do you enjoy the most about like
that Monday to Saturday time frame when
you're digging into all that that game
plan stuff?
>> Just the all the different looks. Every
team's different and um you know, you
never have two weeks that are the same,
so you just dig into it. um get what you
can out of it and um just prepare to the
best of your ability. You know, you're
going to get some unscouted looks and
being able to put that put that puzzle
together and and uh you know, figure it
out and put a hat on a hat. That's it's
pretty cool.
>> There are a lot of stats for offensive
lineman obviously, but one that stands
out is you haven't allowed a sack in in
two years um as as a center. So, I'm
just curious, what do you attribute your
your success in protection to?
Um, man, just going out there and
playing hard, fighting. Um, you know,
you might find yourself in a bad
position, just fighting to get yourself
out of it, keep keep people off your
quarterback. Um, I take pride in that.
You know, I take pride in, um, keeping
the quarterback clean and and, you know,
keeping our backs clean. So,
>> all the time football is football and
there's only so many run plays. When
which one's your favorite when it gets
called?
>> I like duo. I like going going north and
south, but I feel like I can fit into
any scheme, run any scheme. Um, but I
like I like power football going north
and south. So, take us through those,
you know, two hours or whatever it was
before you, you know, agreed to to deal
with the Lions just how frantic is it?
How many teams are calling you? You
know, do you do the Zooms with the teams
or how do you how'd you handle this?
>> Yeah, I let my I let my agent um handle
everything. He did a great job. kept me
in loop with everything. But um I put
everything in his hands and and let him
kind of handle it and I just I just sat
back and um you know let him deal with
it.
>> The final deal or did you have a couple
teams at the end that you
>> Yeah, he he'd have conversations and and
call me and then we'd hash it out and
then he'd you know get back on the phone
and he'd just keep me in the loop and um
we talk things out.
>> Good. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Appreciate y'all.
Hey,
hey, hey.